Mss.B.G61
American Philosophical Society
Hubert Dana Goodale papers
1901-1965
Mss.B.G61
American Philosophical Society
27.0 Linear feet Ca. 11,000 items
In addition to correspondence relating to poultry genetics and egg production, there are significant notes concerning breeding records, heredity, and race genetics. There are 42 class notebooks kept by Goodale, and 62 volumes of Mount Hope Poultry Farm family, hatching, mating records for the period 1918 to 1956. The collection includes photographs, glass-lantern lecture slides, and artifacts of poultry feathers.
Ca. 11,000 items, 27 linear feet.
Goodale, Hubert Dana,1879-
Box 1-34
General note
Table of contents available in Library.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Mrs. H. D. Goodale and Marion P. Goodale, 1969-1972; accessioned, 09/--/1969 and 12/29/1972. See in-house shelf list for additional dates.
Biographical/Historical note
Hubert Dana Goodale (1879–1968) was a poultry and cattle geneticist. From 1922 to 1962, he was the geneticist at the Mount Hope Farm in Williamston, Massachusetts. His main areas of research were the genetics of poultry and milk production, the endocrines of poultry, and the nature of selection and its relation to evolution. Goodale was instrumental in the development of the notion of index breeding, which was based on the principle that demonstrated productive qualities transmitted by any given sire should determine which animals produced the best offspring.
Hubert Goodale was born in Troy, New Hampshire, the son of the Reverend David W. and his wife Mary L. Goodale. He attended Trinity College, Hartford, Connecticut, before enrolling at Columbia University. In 1913 he graduated with a doctorate in biology. During the final two years of his graduate work, Goodale conducted research at the Station for Experimental Evolution at Cold Spring Harbor on Long Island which had been established by the Carnegie Institution in 1904. Goodale subsequently accepted an appointment as research professor in the department of poultry husbandry at the Massachusetts Agricultural Experiment Station. In 1911 he introduced vital staining of the amphibian embryo as a method of tracing the fate of embryonic parts. Goodale left the Station in 1922 in order to become the geneticist at Mount Hope. He held this position for the remainder of his professional life.
Mount Hope farm was owned and managed by E. Parmalee Prentice and his wife Alta Rockefeller Prentice, a daughter of John D. Rockefeller. The couple had established the farm in the 1910s with the express intention to work toward the improvement of agriculture, especially livestock. Goodale’s experimentation at Mount Hope was based on the assumption that the “service that genetics may render to agriculture through improvement in the value of farm animals as a source of income to the farmer is of real importance.” Mount Hope soon became an extensive enterprise primarily known for its “investigation into the laws of inheritance among mice as well as its work with dairy cattle and poultry.” In the farm’s Mouse House, Goodale studied the extent of change accomplished by selection. He used the insights gained from these experiments to help accomplish the farm’s main objective, namely the development of a strictly dairy breed of cattle, i.e., a breed that could pay its way by sales of dairy products alone.
Goodale played a central role in the development of what became known as index breeding. In order to improve the cattle, Mount Hope taught breeders that they should not rely on old standards and pedigree but instead needed to use the progeny test to determine which cattle produced the best offspring. The farm was using the progeny test for the breeding not just of its cattle but also its poultry. It had resulted in a steady increase in the number of eggs produced by the hens. In 1927 Goodale published an article in the American Naturalist in which he announced an index to assist farmers in discovering the productive qualities transmitted by any given dairy bull. The notion of the progeny test undermined the prestige of the “purebred” idea and, not surprisingly, initially met with significant opposition. Goodale’s notion of index breeding was not just new, it also challenged the principles on which significant monetary investments had been made. The new doctrine thus threatened the interests of breeders, auctioneers, breed associations, and others whose welfare depended in large part in the old standards of type and pedigree. In any case, Mount Hope attracted significant attention for its revolutionary idea of index breeding. As the Guernsey Weekly Press acknowledged in 1935, “Mount Hope has become a world-famous center for scientific cattle.”
Partly as a result of a massive campaign designed to educate the public about the benefits of index breeding, the idea gradually found broad popular support. (The publicity even included a feature in the July 1938 issue of Life Magazine, complete with photos of cattle, poultry and Hubert Goodale.) Representatives from as far away as Germany, Italy, Turkey and Sweden visited the farm to learn about its breeding programs. However, it was more challenging to gain the approval of agricultural colleges and government departments. To win their endorsement, Mount Hope hosted a series of regional meetings to discuss the research programs of the Department of Agriculture. Goodale participated in these meetings which ultimately worked to convince the Department of Agriculture to promote progeny-test breeding.
Goodale was a member of the American Society of Zoologists (1914), and the Poultry Science Association. He was married to Lottie Ann Merrill. The couple had two daughters.
Bohren, B. B., (Bernard Benjamin), 1914-; Davenport, Charles Benedict, 1866-1944; Davis, H. P., (Herbert Perry), b. 1889; Demerec, M., (Milislav), 1895-1966; Godfrey, Edward F., (Edward Frelaut), 1924-; Gowen, John Whittemore, 1893-1967; Graham, J. C., (John Campbell), 1912-; Hurst, C. C.(Charles Chamberlain),1870-1947.; Kyle, Wendell H., (Wendell Henry), 1920-; Landauer, Walter, 1896-; Lerner, I. Michael(Isadore Michael),1910-; Morgan, Thomas Hunt, 1866-1945; Mount Hope Poultry Farm.; Nonidez, José F., (José Fernandez), 1892-1947; Prentice, E. Parmalee, (Ezra Parmalee), 1863-1955; Prentice, J. Rockefeller; Smith, Theobald, 1859-1934; Wright, Sewall, 1889-1988; Artifacts.; Breeding -- United States.; Cattle -- Breeding -- United States.; Cattle--Genetics; Chickens -- Breeding -- United States.; Chickens--Genetics; Eggs -- Production.; Eugenics--United States; Feathers; Genetics -- Research -- United States.; Genetics--Experiments; Glass plate negatives; Heredity.; Mice--Breeding; Mice--Genetics; Notebooks.; Photoprints.; Poultry -- Breeding -- United States.; Poultry--Genetics; Race.
- Series I. Correspondence, 1901-1965
  - Abbott, C.G., January 3, 1924
  - Abrams, Ernest R., May 23, 1952
  - Abrams, Frank W., June 21, 1952
  - Acetol Products, Inc., August 22, 1931
  - Ackerson, C.W., January 3, 1927
  - Ackert, James E., August 25, 1925
  - Adams, A. Elizabeth, March-May, 1929
  - Adams, J.P., November 7, 1951
  - Agassiz, Louis, Undated
  - Agersborg, H.P.K., July 15, 1924
  - Agricultural engineering, November 6, 1931
  - Albritton, Errett Cyril, May 27, 1952
  - Allee, W.C., December 20, 1923
  - Allen, Arthur A., May 5, 1950
  - Allen, Willard H., 1924-1950
  - Allyn, H.W., 1931-1933
  - Althouse, Samuel L., 1929-1949
  - Altmann, Margaret, Undated
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1924-1955
  - American Association of Instructors and Investigators in Poultry Husbandry, 1923-1926
  - American Breeders Service Directory, 1953
  - American Breeders Service Newsletter, 1952-1954
  - American Breeders Service-Report G2, 1952-1954
  - American Breeders Service-Sale, May 5, 1951
  - American Council on education., June 14, 1933
  - American Dairy Cattle Club, 1939-1951
  - American Dairy Science Association, 1928
  - American Genetic Association, 1930
  - American Guernsey Cattle Club, 1928-1933
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences., December 4, 1952
  - American Institute of Electrical Engineers, 1932-1933
  - American Institute of Sacred Literature, January 12, 1925
  - American Jersey Cattle Club, May 14, 1934
  - American Magazine, May 5, 1931
  - American Museum of Natural History, August, 1932
  - American Poultry Association, September 17, 1936
  - American Poultry Journal, 1934-1935
  - American Schools Association, July, 1930
  - American Telephone and Telegraph Company, April 15, 1952
  - Amherst Savings Bank, 1925, 1929
  - Anderson, Carl E., March, 1932
  - Angelovich, Victoria, June 25, 1932
  - Appel, Fred W., July 18, 1929
  - Appleton, Francis R, Jr., February, 1930
  - Armour's Livestock Bureau, August 1, 1923
  - Ascanio, Luis, March 13, 1950
  - Ascher, Margaret, March 21, 1949
  - Asmundson, V.S., 1927-1930
  - Association for the Study of Internal Secretions, 1929-1930
  - Atkeson, F.W., December, 1931
  - Atkins, R.C., June 25, 1926
  - Atkinson, M.E., 1923
  - Aubry, Victor G., November, 1925
  - Austin, E.C., June 30, 1951
  - Austin, Lloyd, November, 1942
  - Austin, W.B., May 4, 1926
  - Austin, Warren R., May 3, 1943
  - Australia. Council for Scientific and Industrial Research, September 30, 1942
  - Avery, Tom, Undated
  - Ayrshire Breeders' Association, August 16, 1934
  - Babcock, E.B., 1931-1932
  - Bahrenburg, Charles C, Jr., May 2, 1932
  - Baker, R.K., 1927-1928
  - Baker, Warren S., June, 1941
  - Bakwin, Harry, 1928
  - Bancroft, Margaret, September 7, 1932
  - Banta, A.M., September 2, 1932
  - Banta, Luther, 1923-1951
  - Barber, Harold F., 1925-1931
  - Barents, Margaret, March, 1959
  - Barnes, Arthur M., February 4, 1931
  - Bartlett, J.W., August 4, 1933
  - Basherov, S., 1932-1933
  - Bates, Louis A., 1932-1933
  - Bausch and Lomb Optical Company, July 26, 1927
  - Baxter, William J., May 8, 1951
  - Beach, R.C., 1927-1929
  - Beall, L.C., Jr., January, 1932
  - Bearse, Gordon E., 1927-1928
  - Beatty, William G., April 4, 1934
  - Becker, R.B., 1928-1943
  - Bell, Ellsworth W., February 7, 1950
  - Bell, W., 1930
  - Bennett, H.S., September 9, 1931
  - Bennett, J. Stanley, 1931
  - Benoit, D.J., Undated
  - Benson, Sidney W., February 10, 1953
  - Berner, O., 1923-1924
  - Bernier, P.E., February, 1944
  - Berry, L.N., 1929
  - Bertsch, Howard, 1932
  - Bevan, L.A., 1925
  - Bigelow, M.A., July 2, 1928
  - Biological abstracts, 1926-1931
  - Bird, Charles S, Jr., 1932
  - Bird, H.J., February 24, 1931
  - Birkett, E., September 22, 1944
  - Bissonette, Thomas Hume, April 26, 1933
  - Blackmon, Bruce B., 1943-1944
  - Blackwelder, Eliot, May, 1941
  - Blakeslee, Albert F., 1931-1952
  - Blakiston Company, February 8, 1949
  - Blauvelt, Livingston, 1929-1930
  - Blood, Howard E., March 19, 1935
  - Blyth, Janet S.S., April 7, 1952
  - Boardman, Edgar, 1925-1926
  - Bohren, B.B., 1949-1952
  - Boland, E.N., January, 1932
  - Boss, Gerhard, July 15, 1936
  - Boston Post, April 18, 1925
  - Botsford, H.E., March 13, 1929
  - Bottum, N.D., 1922-1946
  - Bouillet, S., July 28, 1924
  - Boutflour, R., January 29, 1949
  - Bowen, Byron D., October 10, 1925
  - Bowen, Robert H., February 18, 1927
  - Bowstead, J.E., September, 1932
  - Bradley, R.C., July 5, 1933
  - Branion, H.D., 1952-1953
  - Brant, Rancho, May 6, 1933
  - Braun, Edward, August 5, 1930
  - Breneman, W.R., February 13, 1948
  - Bridges, Styles, May 3, 1943
  - Brigham, Henry D., 1933
  - Briggs, Robert W., 1943
  - Brill, W.F., 1928-1929
  - Brink, R.A., 1932-1933
  - Brody, Elizabeth Graves, 1942-1943
  - Brosemer, L.J., 1949
  - Brown, Royer H., 1932
  - Brown, Russell V., 1963
  - Brown, W.A., June 5, 1925
  - Bruce, Ellsworth, April 15, 1930
  - Bruchlos, Werner C., 1941-1942
  - Bryn Mawr Horse Show Association, 1932
  - Buchanan Smith, A.D., 1927-1932
  - Buchholz, A.B., 1933-1934
  - Buckeye Incubator Company, 1924-1927
  - Buckler, John, 1926-1927
  - Buick Motor Company, January 15, 1934
  - Bullis, Kenneth L., 1930-1937
  - Bureau of biological survey, June 28, 1930
  - Burgess, Charles G., August 17, 1923
  - Burgess, Laura, January 19, 1948
  - Burnett, Robert J., 1930-1931
  - Burzens, A.W., Undated
  - Bush, Guy L., November, 1929
  - Bywaters, J.H., 1932
  - Caldwell, Otis William, April 1, 1933
  - Callenbach, E.W., 1928-1931
  - Campbell, M.H., September 29, 1928
  - Campbell, P.A., August 11, 1930
  - Campos, Louis G., Undated
  - Card, L.E., 1924-1935
  - Cardiff, Ira D., February 22, 1950
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, May 31, 1929
  - Carpenter, D.C., 1931-1932
  - Carpenter, Earle S., November 15, 1930
  - Carrick, C.W., 1932-1936
  - Carver, J.S., 1925-1926
  - Casella, Giuseppe, 1932-1933
  - Castle, William Ernest, 1929-1950
  - Cattell, James McKean, 1923-1942
  - Cattell, Jaques, 1942-1949
  - Certified Milk Official Magazine, 1931
  - Chandler, Henry P., February 12, 1929
  - Chapman, Walter William, January 1, 1925
  - Charles, T.B., 1930-1946
  - Chase, Richard, January, 1928
  - Chatillon, John, & Sons, 1931
  - Chen, Shisan C., December 13, 1923
  - Chen Kang, Chai, March 18, 1949
  - Churchill, Ralph, July 17, 1943
  - Chute, R.M., February 22, 1954
  - Clark, Byron H., October, 1942
  - Clark, Russell A., October, 1950
  - Clements, Norris C., June 23, 1933
  - Clogg, Oscar G., November 5, 1934
  - Cobb, Robert C., 1928
  - Cobb, Stanley, February 9, 1948
  - Cockell, Fred H., 1935-1957
  - Coe, R.L., September 8, 1926
  - Cole, L.J., 1929-1934
  - Cole, Lamont C., December 15, 1952
  - Collins, W.M., November, 1951
  - Columbia Alumni Fund, 1929, 1949
  - Columbia University, 1954, 1956
  - Condron, Michael H., March 21, 1949
  - Conklin, C.T., 1930-1934
  - Connecticut General Life Insurance Company, 1926-1929
  - Consumers Research, 1932
  - Cook, Robert C., 1930-1935
  - Cook, Walter H., April 25, 1925
  - Cooke, John H., March 5, 1927
  - Cooper Hewitt Electric Company, 1925, 1927
  - Copeland, Lynn, 1929-1932
  - Copeland, O.C., July 27, 1931
  - Corning Glass Works, 1926, 1927
  - Cory, Campbell L., 1926-1927
  - Country Gentleman, March 5, 1953
  - Cowie, W.G., July, 1931
  - Cox, Charles M., Company, 1950-1954
  - Cox, Hiden T., November, 1953
  - Craig, Emma, January 29, 1924
  - Crampton, Henry Edward, December 4, 1942
  - Cray, Raymond E., June 26, 1926
  - Crew, Frank A.E., 1927-1930
    General note
    See: table of contents
  - Cripps, Ralph W., May 28, 1928
  - Crittenden, Lyman B., April 3, 1953
  - Crockett, Doris L., June 3, 1927
  - Crozier, William John, December 29, 1923
  - Dahlberg, A.C., 1930-1934
  - Dairy Herd Improvement Association, 1953
  - Dakan, E.L., 1927-1930
  - Danforth, Charles Haskell, August 27, 1949
  - Davenport, Charles Benedict, 1911-1935
  - Davenport, W.H., Undated
  - Davidson, Fred A., April 14, 1927
  - Davis, C.C., 1932-1933
  - Davis, Charles H., June 28, 1928
  - Davis, Charles P., Mrs., 1931-1932
  - Davis, Everett F., March 2, 1937
  - Davis, H.P., 1933-1941
  - Davis, J.H.K., November 20, 1926
  - Davis, R.L., 1929
  - Deakin, Alan, April, 1932
  - Dearden, Douglas M., January 27, 1948
  - Decker, Frank N., July 31, 1934
  - Delancey, James J., March 29, 1951
  - Demerec, Milislav, 1932-1936
  - Dempster, Everett Ross, 1949-1964
  - Denise, Theo. E., January 12, 1929
  - Dibble, Benjamin, July 17, 1936
  - Dick, G.A., August 14, 1931
  - Dickerson, G.E., 1945, 1964
  - Dickie, W.L., July 12, 1930
  - Dill, Homer R., 1929, 1931
  - Ditlefsen, J.A., January 15, 1926
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius Gregorievich, 1949, 1964
  - Dodds, Richard, 1927-1928
  - Domm, L.V., March 25, 1933
  - Donaldson, Frederick A., August, 1932
  - Dorcas, H.C., June 25, 1931
  - Dougherty, J.E., June 26, 1923
  - Douglas, Gertrude E., June 10, 1936
  - Dow, George F., December, 1964
  - Downham, K.D., June 9, 1931
  - Doyle, Martin N., Undated
  - Dry, F.S., June, 1944
  - Dry, F.W., 1943, 1946
  - Dryden, Horace W., February 27, 1935
  - Dryden, James, June 25, 1924
  - Dryden, W.J., 1925-1927
  - Dublin, Louis Israel, January 14, 1924
  - Dunkerly, J.D., June 22, 1928
  - Dunn, Harland K., 1949, 1952
  - Dunn, Leslie Clarence, 1924-1950
  - East, Edward Murray, 1931-1937
  - Eckstein, B.R., Undated
  - Eddy, Walter H., January 29, 1924
  - Edwards, Charles Lincoln, 1901-1934
  - Edwards, Jessie S., Undated
  - Edwards, John R., May 23, 1937
  - Edwards, Joseph, 1930-1931
  - Edwards, Richard, May 17, 1937
  - Eglise, Charles, Jr., January, 1942
  - Ehmann, Frans E., October 23, 1930
  - Eiduson, Samuel, March, 1966
  - Eimer & Amend, 1931-1934
  - Eiseley, Loren C., March 15, 1950
  - Eldridge, Franklin, November 6, 1943
  - Electric Incubator Company, June, 1926
  - Elford, Fred C., 1930-1932
  - Ellington, E.V., September 12, 1928
  - Ellis, Carleton, December 1, 1926
  - Elmhurst, Leonard K., November 30, 1929
  - Emerson, Kendall, April, 1941
  - Emlen, John T., Undated
  - Emmel, M.W., July 27, 1934
  - Endocrine survey, April 25, 1927
  - Eugenics Committee of the U.S.A., 1923-1925
  - Evans, Alfred H., 1929
  - Evans, Herbert M., January 10, 1928
  - Evershade Orchards & Poultry Farm, 1950
  - Falconer, D.S., 1947-1948
  - Fall, Paul H., 1941
  - Fall River Savings Bank, August 9, 1928
  - The Farm Journal, June 19, 1929
  - Fawcett, C.J., December 5, 1927
  - Feathered World, 1936-1937
  - Fernald, H.T., 1902, 1925
  - Fernekorn, Fred, July 2, 1932
  - Fiato, Luigi, 1932-1933
  - Fischer, Charles, February 17, 1943
  - Fisher, B.K., July 27, 1931
  - Fisher, R.A., 1931-1948
  - Fisk, Eugene Lyman, January 18, 1924
  - Fitch, J.B., February 9, 1928
  - Fitts, H.B., 1928-1932
  - Fletcher, R.E., May, 1926
  - Flint, Oliver S., 1929
  - Follett, Spencer, April 29, 1932
  - Foote, Stanely S., August 17, 1924
  - Ford, Waldo B., 1927
  - Forman, Kenneth W., December 11, 1936
  - Forsythe, W.E., June 10, 1927
  - Foster, James Q., September 24, 1934
  - Four College Genetic Conference, October 4, 1949
  - Fox, Thomas W., 1952, 1963
  - Franksden, V.H., June, 1931
  - Fraser, Alexander, February 25, 1964
  - Fraser, Carl A., 1928
  - Freeman, Stanley L., 1954
  - Freeman, W.H., and Company, August 14, 1952
  - French, A.P., 1948-1949
  - Friends of Medical Progress, Inc., April 24, 1924
  - Fullingim, Archer, April 25, 1932
  - Fyler, Wadsworth G., August 9, 1927
  - Gage, Brownell, 1927, 1932
  - Gage, G.E., October 13, 1933
  - Gaines, W.L., 1927-1941
  - Gallant, James F., 1931, 1941
  - Gardner, Shirley E., 1952, 1954
  - Garrard, Warren, 1951
  - Garrett, Henry E., January 23, 1950
  - Gavian, Sarkis P., October 31, 1931
  - Geer, P.W., April 9, 1935
  - Geer, R.H., August 1, 1925
  - General Electric Company, 1927, 1933
  - General Motors Corporation, 1934
  - Geneticists interested in agriculture, February 4, 1926
  - Genetics (Journal), January 28, 1930
  - Genetics Society of America, October 19, 1935
  - Gerould, J.H., March 15, 1950
  - Gibbs, Charles S, 1930, 1933
  - Gifford, Warren, 1931
  - Gilbert, H.P., March 15, 1924
  - Gilpin, Douglas, 1931
  - Ginsburgh, Sylvan J., 1933, 1934
  - Globus, Joseph, 1929-1932
  - Glover, A.J., 1932, 1937
  - Godfrey, Edward F., 1952-1966
  - Gofman, John W., 1950-1952
    See also: Journal of Experimental Medicine, in:
  - Goodale, Hazel, February 11, 1936
  - Goode, Frank, June, 1930
  - Goodman, John W., December, 1929
  - Goodnow, Lewis W., December, 1928
  - Gorbman, Aubrey, January 7, 1954
  - Gortner, Ross Aiken, 1914, 1931-1932
  - Gosney, Ezra Seymour, June 15, 1934
  - Gould, William H., October, 1931
  - Gowen, John W., 1926-1953
  - Graham, J.C. #1, 1912-1924
  - Graham, J.C. #2, 1925-1931
    See: Lutz
  - Graham, J.C. #3, 1932-1942
  - Graham, Leland J., 1923
  - Graham, W.R., 1933, 1937
  - Granger, G., 1931
  - Grant, Loyal W., 1928, 1932
  - Graves, R.R., 1929
  - Gray, Jack E., 1953
  - Gray, Richard W., April 17, 1925
  - Green, G.R., June, 1933
  - Greenbaum, M.J., December 17, 1923
  - Greenman, M.J., December 21, 1923
  - Grierson, Margaret, May 13, 1930
  - Griffee, Fred, 1930
  - Griffin, Donald R., December, 1952
  - Gruenberg, Benjamin C., 1929-1930
  - Gruneberg, Hans, October, 1949
  - Guilford, Everett, June 18, 1929
  - Gulliver, Harold, May 12, 1933
  - Gunne, J.R., September 1, 1932
  - Gustafson, D.A.H., 1952
  - Gutteridge, H.S., August 11, 1930
  - Guyer, M.F., 1931
  - Hadley, P.B., 1912
  - Hagar, W.S., 1931
  - Hagedorn, A.L., May 21, 1936
  - Haight, Austin D., October 28, 1936
  - Hall Brothers Hatchery, Inc., 1941, 1950
  - Halpin, J.G., 1924, 1925
  - Hammett, Frederick S., Undated
  - Handley, Pattii, 1924-1925
  - Hanke, Oscar August, March 16, 1953
  - Hannas, Ralston R., 1937, 1944
  - Hanovia Chemical & Manufacturing Co., January 17, 1924
    See also: Thorndike, Augustus, in:
  - Hansen, Henry J., September 2, 1936
  - Harland, S.C., 1924, 1957-1958
  - Harper, F.A., April, 1950
  - Harper, M.W., April, 1929
  - Harper's Magazine, March 3, 1953
  - Harris, Isaac F., 1924
  - Harris, J. Arthur, 1922-1924
  - Harris, Roy T., 1930
  - Harrow, Benjamin, Undated
  - Harrowes, L.B., November 29, 1927
  - Hayes, J.B., July 16, 1937
  - Hays, Frank A., 1922-1957
  - Hayward, H., September 19, 1929
  - Hayward, Lillian W., April 17, 1932
  - Hayward, Richard H., 1931?
  - Hazard, F.R., January, 1934
  - Healy, Winston, March 23, 1935
  - Heisdorf and Nelson Farm, June 1950
  - Heizer, E.E., 1931-1935
  - Hemmingson, Arthur, January 31, 1927
  - Henderson, Earl W., 1950
  - Henderson, Peter & Company, 1927
  - Hendricks, Bartlett, February 15, 1949
  - Henry, Colin J.B., September 2, 1963
  - Herald Tribune [New York], December 17, 1934
  - Hershey, H.L., December 27, 1932
  - Hertzler, Emanuel C., July 15, 1949
  - Hervey, George W., April 16, 1926
  - Heuser, Gustave F., 1931
  - Hevesh, Jack, 1934
  - Hicks, Amp F., Jr., 1951
  - Hicks, Reese V., September 24, 1928
  - Hill, B.F., Jr., January 16, 1953
  - Hill Girt Farm, 1932
  - Hill, J. Ben, 1952
  - Hill, R.L., 1931
  - Hill, Ruth, December 1, 1933
  - Hinshaw, W.R., 1928-1929
  - Hirsch, Jerry, December 20, 1963
  - Hitchcock, Harold B., 1954, 1962
  - Hoard's Dairyman, 1928, 1944
  - Hobson, Howard, 1932
  - Hoch, Joseph F., December, 1931
  - Hocker, G. Henry, 1928
  - Hollis, Sumner D., February 13, 1926
  - Holm, John A., January 28, 1926
  - Holmes, Carl F., 1932
  - Holstein-Friesian Ass'n of America, 1930-1933
  - Holstein-Friesian World, July 28, 1932
  - Homeyer, W.C., March 17, 1925
  - Hook, Robert, 1931
  - Hooker, D.R., 1926-1927
  - Horton, Byron B., 1912
  - Horton, D.H., 1928-1944
  - Hoskins, Roy G., January, 1947
  - Hovey, Edmund Otis, July 24, 1912
  - Howie, James M., October, 1949
  - Hubbard, George C., May 22, 1924
  - Hubbard, Malvern, October, 1935
  - Hubbard, P.J., January 23, 1929
  - Hubbard, Wentworth, February 22, 1956
  - Hubbs, Carl L., 1937
  - Huffman, C.F., 1924
  - Hughes, J.S., July 15, 1925
  - Hughes, R.M., September 13, 1933
  - Hughs, James M., 1925
  - Hull, Clark L., 1926
  - Hurd, L.M., 1932
  - Hurst, Charles Chamberlain, 1923
  - Hutchinson, W.C., November 30, 1934
  - Hutt, Frederick Bruce, 1932-1964
  - Hyland, Ruth, 1957
  - Illinois Holstein Friesian Ass'n, Inc., May 10, 1933
  - Ingalls, Theodore H., February 19, 1952
  - Inman, C.C., March 3, 1932
  - International Agricultural Corporation, December 2, 1927
  - International Baby Chick Association, March 20, 1930
  - International Business Machines Corporation, 1930-1931
  - International Products Corporation, March 19, 1931
  - Irvin, Roy, September 21, 1925
  - Ithaca Sales and Pedigree Company, 1927-1928
  - Ives, Phillip G., August 22, 1931
  - Jaap, R. George, 1948
  - Jackson, Homer W., 1924-1928
  - Jackson, Roscoe B., Memorial Laboratory, 1948-1953
  - Jacoby, Henry S., January 24, 1929
  - Jenness, Arthur, December 12, 1951